Andrey Tell us that this to our long-
Андрей Скажи нам что нам этот нашему
suffering poor Russian
многострадальному бедному русскому
people, what should we do,
народу что делать-то
nothing can be done,
ничего уже не сделать
we need to quickly destroy the Russian
нужно побыстрее развалить Российскую
Federation
Федерацию
Hello Hello
Здравствуйте Здравствуйте Вы
Where are you from? I'm from Russia I'm from Makhachkala, the
откуда Я из России Я из Махачкалы
wax city,
воскового города
something is somehow strange Makhachkala and the
что-то как-то странно Махачкала и
Jewish flag in the back I mean  so in
еврейский флаг сзади В смысле так в
Derbent Well, I come from Derbent myself.
Дербенте Ну сам родом из Дербента
Derbent is one of the most ancient
Дербент - Это один из самых древних
cities in Russia where Jews lived and from
городов России где евреи жили и спокон
time immemorial, wait  about this, I
веков подожди я насчёт этого Я насчёт
don’t argue about this, that Jews lived there, let’s say,
этого не спорю что там евреи допустим
not me, you remember
проживали не я этот име помнишь
Makhachkala. Yes, there
Махачкале Да было Тода
was a pogrom. We didn’t go out. The fact is that the authorities there guarded our synagogue because in both Derbent and Makhachkala they guarded the synagogue because there was a pogrom
охраняли синагогу потому что был погром
yes, he was somewhere and now recently,
да такой а где-то и сейчас недавно был
also in Dagestan,
тоже в Дагестане
uh, like some sons or
ээ типа какие-то или сыновья
relatives of or this is when When they
родственники у или у это когда Когда
shot
расстреляли
Yes, that’s even earlier, it wouldn’t have
Да это ещё это ещё раньше бы не это
been that later, it was later, yes, it wasn’t them, and in
позже позже было да это было не они
my opinion, I think I just don’t know. In
причём по-моему Вроде только не знаю В
the synagogue, not in the synagogue, but it seems that in the church there were
синагоге не в синагоге но вроде в церкви
separate ceremonies there.
разделялись цер там было
Well, you know, we have Dagestan,
было Ну у нас понимаешь у нас Дагестан
in general, a very complex region
вообще сложный регион очень
multinational there Avars Dargins
многонациональный там аварцы даргинцы
Kumyks Ilak Tabasarans Jew everything is
кумыки илак табасаранцы еврей все есть
Dadada I know that And you, I see, your
дадада это я знаю А вы я так смот вы по
nationality is also
национальности тоже
ours
наш наш
and
а
who I am is Pomor Pomor I know  Yes, there are Pomors, there are
кто я помор помор знаю да помор северяне
such northerners, yes, I understand the Pomors of the North, it’s
такие есть да Вот я севера помор понял
interesting, Pomors, well, maybe our
интересно помор нуно там может тоже наши
Jews were also once there, or the Pomors were
евреи были порами когда-то или поморы
Jews, no, we don’t have any Jews, I understand,
евреями нет у нас евреев нету понял К
Unfortunately, we don’t, we understand, and there the Russians are
сожалению нет у нас понял а там русски
oppressing
по притесняют
us too.  you are a multinational
м у на тоже и у вас многонациональный
region, what city do you live in now,
раон вы сейчас в каком городе жите у нас
look here we have, as it were, Russian
здесь смотрите у нас как бы русские
Pomors, Ukrainians,
поморы украинцы
Belarusians Well, we even have a region
белорусы Ну у нас даже регион это
called Nenets, that is
называется Ненецкий то есть
Germans Kalmyks Kazakhs
немцы калмыки казахи
Chechens Well, especially from the Caucasus
чеченцев Ну вот Особенно с Кавказа
in general, I watched the news that in Tyumen the
вообще я я смотрел новости что в Тюмени
most popular name for boys is
самое популярное имя мальчиков - это
Muhammad at birth,
Мухаммад при рождении
but here we have this one called
получается нет А у нас так этот как его
Vasya, recently a survey was conducted by
Вася вот недавно опрос вели
this girl Katya, well, after newborns it’s
этот девочка Катя ну по новорождённым
called And after boys  ly
назват А по мальчикам лий
quite such a common Russian Pomeranian name
довольно такое русско поморское имя
Vasya
распространённое Вася
yes yes Vasily Vasily Well, in principle, yes
да да Василий Василий Ну в принципе да
it is translated from Pomeranian  in Russian
это в переводе с поморского на русский
it means king Balius was
означает царь балиус был
basileus right damn you are right this one yes in
базилевс верно блин вы правы этот да на
Greek it is king
гречески это царь
yes well and the level is also that I am a linguist
да ну и уров тоже в том что я лингвист
myself I have 18 years of practice in 2 years
сам у меня 18 лет практики через 2 года
it will be the twentieth I graduated from
будет двадцатой я заканчивал
St. Petersburg State
санкт-петербургский государственный
University Faculty of Linguistics and here
университет факультет лингвистики и вот
you are  Do you know your own Pomeranian language or do
вы свой поморский язык знаете или уже
you already have mostly Russian?
русский в основном у вас
And I’m like, roughly speaking,
А я как бы тут грубо говоря поморского
there is no Pomeranian language here, he has his own dialect,
языка нету он у него свой этот э диалект
well, you know
ну э знаете
Lomonosov's Lomonos you know we know he's
ломоно Ломоносова знаете знаем он же
one of the most famous Pomors Yes so
один из самых известных поморов Да так
uh Lomonosov look Lomonos we love
вот ээ Ломоносов смотрите ломоно любим
Yes yes Lomonosov also spoke the
Да да Ломоносов ещё разговаривал на
Pomeranian language and he has some
поморской языке и у него есть некоторые
treatises written in the Pomorian language at the
трактаты написанные на поморской языке в
uh Moscow State
ээ Московском государственном
University in the scientific library the
университете в научной библиотеке
originals of his treatises are kept Yes  we
хранятся оригиналы его трактатов Да мы
got acquainted because we studied and uh
знакомились потому что мы изучали и э
we just had
как раз у нас было
uh taught two semesters on Morikawa
ээ преподавали два семестра по морикава
Well, the subject is
Ну предмет
about studying
о изучении
uh the language of the Pomors and  right now Well, as I
э языка поморов и вот сейчас Ну я так
understand it, you speak completely in Russian You speak
понимаю вы полностью по-русски Говорите
Yes, yes, but Lamanosov
Да да вот а у ламаносова вот в языке
still had Lomonosov in the language because he then
Ломоносова ещё был потому что он потом
studied at the Kiev-Mohyla Academy,
учился в киево-могилянской академии
then he was sent to Europe and he already
потом его отправили в Европу и он уже
made a grammar of the Russian language And so And it
сделал грамматику русского языка А так А
is possible  I'll interrupt
можно я вас перебью
you, what's your name Andrey
да Вас как зовут Андрей
Andrey, wow, you're so smart Andrey Well,
Андрей хуя ты умный Андрей какой Ну ну
let's listen to you further, I understand, I understand
давай дальше тебя послушаю понял понял
So
Так вот
look in the Pomeranian language, for example, here
смотри на поморской языке например вот
Say something  a simple phrase because it’s
Скажи какую-то фразу простую потому что
complex I don’t chick don’t say it in Russian and
сложные я не чикать не скажи по-русски а
I’ll translate it for you into
я тебе переведу на
Pomeranian not I’m telling you in
поморский не я тебе говорю на
Pomeranian it’s a dialect that’s already modern
поморское это диалект уже современный
that something Probably you came up with I don’t know
что что-то Наверное вы придумали не знаю
chishka to write it Well it’s modern it’s
чишка это писать Ну это современно это
a swear word yes like chishka Probably  this
ругательство да типа чишка Наверное это
is not a curse, this is from me, this is from
это не ругательство это у меня Это с
childhood, so I’ll let you go to the village
детства так вот я допустиму в деревню
when my grandmother flew in. Well, go go, I
как прилетал мня бабушка Ну иди сходи я
was still little, go go, I
ещё маленький был иди сходи по чикой я
understand why, you know why  you know why?
понял знаешь почему вот знаешь почему
Because look, the male genital organ
Потому что смотри мужской половой орган
in Pomeranian is chishka, that’s why
по поморски - это чиш всё Поэтому и
chishka is cool, now you’re doing
чишка вот это прикольно ты сейчас сам
it yourself No no no no no Look, I didn’t know
это Нет нет нет нет нет Смотри я не знал
the word chishka, yes, I immediately understood the root Yes,
слово чишка да я сразу понял корень Да
chishka is chishka, and zani is  puff chush and puff
чиш - это чиш а зани - это пыш чиш и пыш
But for now it’s about Pyshka I don’t know how to poop
А пока это по Пышка не Как какать не
But the body parts are puffy because we
знаю А вот части тела пыш потому что мы
studied the parts of the body because we didn’t Well since it’s
части тела изучали потому что не Ну раз
not me I’ll explain, look  The thing is,
раз чиш не я Я объясню смотри дело в том
I don’t know how it will drink Yes, that’s what you’re
я не знаю как будет пить Да вот это ты
burning chick I just know how parts of the
горишь чишка Просто я знаю как части
body are because Lomonosov made an atla
тела потому что Ломоносов он сделал атла
with human anatomy and signed it in
с анатомией человека и подписал на
Pomeranian language like a hand Like a leg like
поморской языке как рука Как нога как
a head like chish
голова как чиш
puff Look
пыш Вот смотри
uh fish in Pomeranian  how
ээ рыба по поморский как
will cod not not fish fshu fshu popo
будет треска не не рыба фшу фшу попо
sea Forsh fou it is very similar to the
морски Форш фоу оно очень схоже с
English Fish something Yes, perhaps
английским Фиш чем-то Да вот возможно
there are some here in ours
есть некоторые вот в у нас в
St. Petersburg State
санкт-петербургском государственном
University there is uh Ivan uh Ternov he's a
университете есть ээ Иван ээ тернов он
Pomor himself he's a Pomor himself and he, well, he's our
сам помор он сам помор и он ну он у нас
department on Moriki just uh he headed
кафедру по морики как раз ээ возглавлял
uh He deduced that in the English language
ээ Он выводил что в английском языке
there are some words borrowed from
есть часть слов заимствовано из
Pomeranian Why Because the Pomor and the
поморского Почему Потому что помор и
English had contacts  including,
англичане имели контакты в то том числе
and by the way, can I
и вот кстати можно я ещё
interrupt you about contacts in our
перебью вот насчёт контактов у нас в
city in 1800 some year? Well, our city is
городе 1800 каком-то году Ну у нас город
Pustozersk  was, as it were, founded and
пустозерск был как бы основан и вот как
just on the territory of our city we
раз таки территории нашего города у нас
had a timber mill. We floated pure timber from
был лесозавод Мы чисто лес сплавлять с
Komi and sold it abroad, and the
Коми и продавали за границу и построили
Dutch built it, this factory, well, in their day, it’s like they
его голландцы этот завод ну на их день
built it and transported timber abroad
как бы это строили и возили за границу
Yes, there is such a thing Yes A  how will it be in
Да есть такое Да А как будет по
Pomeranian father
поморский отец
you know I don’t
знаешь не
know tatur
знаю татур
Tato Well ta
Тато Ну та
tar tar
тар тар
tar and Lomonosov also has a poem in
тар и у Ломоносова ещё есть стих на
Pomeranian it’s called dedication to the father
поморской он называется посвящение отцу
e peto Ta
э пето Та
tor already something in Greek  spoke
тору уже что-то по-гречески заговорил
no peto Tato - this is Lamonosov's
нет пето Тато - это у ламоносова его
most famous verse or or whatever it is in
самый известный стих или или как его по
Latin not this is the most famous verse in the
латински не это самый известный стих на
Pomeranian language Well, as the most famous The
поморской языке Ну как самый известный
fact is that of all the recordings of the
Дело в том что из всех записей
Pomorian language this is only what
поморского языка это только то что
Monosov wrote down
записывал моносов
left Andrey Why me why  I now
осталось Андрей Почему я почему я сечас
Well, I kind of consider myself like Mora Because
Ну как бы считаю себя по Мора Потому что
my family Yes, here we have villages along the
мой род Да вот у нас это деревни по
coast of the Barents
побережью Баренца
Sea,
моря вот
they are 200, well, more than 200
им 200 ну 200 с лишним
years old, that is, it was still roughly speaking
лет то есть это было ещё грубо говоря
even  to the Russian Empire
даже до Российской империи
Uh-huh So I kind of think that most
Угу Вот я как бы и считаю что скорее
likely, well, I have a mouth too, as if
всего ну и и рот-то у меня тоже как бы
he’s been living there for more than one generation, as if, well,
он не одно поколение там живёт как бы ну
more like we’re from
больше как с
the Mezen from the Mezen
Мезень с мезени
Yes, it’s interesting What is your
мы Да интересно А какая вот у вас
most important Pomor  the Pomeranian
поморов самый главный поморский
city of
город
Arkhangelsk
Архангельск
understood Well, I think so Arkhangelsk well yes Yes,
понял Ну я так думаю архангельс ну да Да
everything is correct, I just translated it, I
всё правильно я я просто перевел
checked it or are you a Pomor really
проверял или ты помор действительно
interesting No, it’s as if the fact is that
интересно Не ну как бы Дело в том что у
we still have the center of Arkhangelsk
нас до сих пор центр-то Архангельский
Yes  Listen and I watch. You know, Russia is
Да Слушай и я смотрю Знаешь Россия она
a little involved in oppressing the Pomors.
немножко занимается угнетением поморов
In the Arkhangelsk region, there is still
Вот в Архангельской области до сих пор
no gas supply, even
не газифицирован даже
well,
ну вот
look, this one, you are now
смотрите вот вот этот вот ты сейчас
dealing,
занимаешься
roughly
грубо
speaking, with the disintegration of society,
говоря разложение общества
yes. Well, you see, you even admit this, yes,
да Ну видишь ты даже это признаёшь да я
even I even agree that it’s Russian  the people of the
даже я Даже согласен что русский народ
oppressed time were screwed up before,
угнетённое время напортачили раньше вот
these are all the territories where I
эти все территории где вот я сейчас
live now, they were the Arkhangelsk
проживаю они были Архангельская
Province and Komi captured all this
Губерния и и Коми захватывала всё это
atom
атом
after the revolution this is the Armed Forces  divided, as it
после революции это ВС вот разделили как
were, along national lines, as if
бы по национальному признаку как бы
according to small
по по малым
nationalities,
народном
and I see you, too, are doing exactly
вот А ты я смотрю тоже занимайся именно
what the national Motherland is. Yes, yes, well,
что национальной Родине Да да да Ну вот
you see, I know
видишь зна
I studied at the faculty in St.
Я учился на факультете у себя в
Petersburg,
Питере у
our dean is
нас наш декан
so
так
inid
инид
Joshua gori No, he is Georgian Joshua  ioni And
Джошуа гори Нет он грузин Джошуа иони А
what do you don’t like, that it’s not like he
что ты Тебе не нравится что не как это
said it’s Georgian, or that Georgian Yes,
сказал он грузин или что грузин Да
Georgian, what interests you, that it’s early, that
грузин что тебя интересует что ранно что
there are Georgians in the Soviet Union Yes, it was
тере грузины в Советском Союзе Да были
like that with us  Stalin was the
так у нас у нас Сталин был грузи гори
commander-in-chief, so
главнокомандующий было таскать так вот и
look, he said that
смотри он говорил что
earlier, on the territory of the modern
э Вот раньше на территории современной
Russian Federation, a
Российской Федерации проживало
huge number of different peoples lived with
огромнейшее количество разных народов со
their own cultures, and when the Muscovite
своими культурами да И когда московие
kingdom began to seize everything, it
царство начало захватывать всё оно
began to destroy and melt them into a
начало уничтожать и переплавлять их в
single, faceless substrate, therefore
Единый такой безликий субстрат поэтому
in order to wait in order to
для того чтобы подожди для того чтобы
save the cultural diversity of the planet
спасти культурное разнообразие планеты
So we must break up the Russian
Так мы должны развалить Российскую
Federation into small national
Федерацию на небольшие национальные
states so And look at this  here And
государства так А смотри вот это вот А
about this, I understand you that you
насчёт этого Я тебя понял то что ты
are engaged in the collapse of Russia, as if
занимаешься развалом России как бы на ну
you are a supporter of the division of Russia, yes, that’s
на на на ты сторонник деления России да
correct, not just a supporter but an active
правильно не то что сторонник а активный
divider, well, in short, well, it’s understandable,
делитель актив ну короче ну понятно это
roughly speaking How can I call you igen
грубо говоря Как тебя обозвать иген
in short igen yes yes that’s it  And look,
короче иген да да вот А смотрите
call me Igen
Называйте меня иген
Smoktunovsky Smoktunovsky okay And
Смоктуновский Смоктуновский ладно А это
what about
как
him? Well, let’s
его вот насчёт Ну допустим глубже
go deeper. Yes, this is when,
углубиться Да вот это когда
well, Tartaria. Well, let’s say we
вот ну Тартария Да вот допустим у нас
don’t seem to have this
вроде как нету вот этой
history of some kind
истории каких-то
foreign ones there in France There is this one in
зарубежных там во Франции Там этот в
London somewhere there are maps that a map
Лондоне там где-то карты есть что карта
Yes a map of the plan Yes it says Tartary
Да карта плана Да там написано Тартария
and what is being said right now is
да то что вот сейчас это речь-то идёт
that the Tatars have a Mongol yoke there for
что вот татара монгольская ига там вот
300 years and they were sitting there under it But here
300 лет было да там под ним сидели А вот
now, as it were, modern scientists, well,
сейчас-то как бы современные учёные ну
like Russian ones, say that there
как бы типа российские говорят что это
was no
не было
such thing, well, like a civil war
никакого это ну типа гражданская война
was going on, as if it used to be the state of
шла как бы это раньше было государство
Tartary, it went right up to South
Тартария она вплоть Ну что на Южную
America, oh  North America
Америку уходила ой на Северную Америку
was leaving and right up to India, part of
уходила и вплоть до Индии там часть
China
Китая
occupied there. Well, very much, well, how the
занимала Ну очень большо ну как
Giant state was and then, as you
Гигантское государство было и потом как
can see in some x, and then that these are the
видать в каких-то х и то что вот
territories that Russia is now and
территории что Россия сейчас и вот
this one there we gave to the Americans Alaska,
этот отдали там мы американцам Аляску
roughly speaking, this is the West, these  how
грубо говоря это Запада вот эти как они
are they all relatives?
же все родственники были
knife Sorry, I was scared or something Yes, when a
ножик Извини испугался что ли Да когда
Jew with a knife is a little not
на еврея с ножиком то немножко не
funny Well, I just see, put it
прикольно А ну я просто вишь положи
down, put it down, put it down Yes, stories that
положи положи положи его Да рассказы что
there from the West to the Jew that from
там Запада еврею что с
the West that's what, well
Запада вот что ну
T all the relatives are all
Т все родственники все э
rito under Listen to me how and then I'm
рито подо Послушай меня как е потом я
your opinion as
твоё мнение как
smart That's what we have is
умного Вот и то что у нас это
Pugachev's Uprising That was it
пугачёвское Восстание Вот это было Да
Why, some peasants
что там какие-то крестьяне
rebelled, then they
это восстали их потом
were suppressed  mos
подавили мос
know And so that Puv would be just the
зна И что бы пув был как раз таки
representative of the Tartars, this is
представитель тартари это
the state that the West This is what the Armed Forces
государства то что Запада Вот это ВС
calls this, this is what they had, as
вот называет вот это вот что у них как
if they fought And
бы они воевали И в итоге эту верхушку
in the end, they finished off this top of Tartaria and then this territory simply seemed to mean that Russia as a state did not exist, then Peter I came up with something like the Russian Empire in order to Primarily to the history of Rus' Yes, it was the Great Tartary, if we look at all the maps it everything is Great Tartary because it was the territory of the Golden Horde, that is, the modern Kazakh Tatars and so on, the Turkic peoples Moscow Moscow was founded by the khan  Mengu Timur yes as a
основана ханом менгу Тимуром да как
collection point for Denmark with the Finno-Ugric
пункт сбора Дании с фино угорских
peoples Yes, uh then when
народов Да ээ потом когда
uh the Empire of the Golden Horde weakened a little
ээ Империя Золотой Орды немножко ослабла
uh a civil war began in it, that
э в ней начались гражданская война то
is,
есть
uh Moscow wanted to separate from the Golden
ээ Москва захотела отделиться от Золотой
Horde in order to collect tribute from other
Орды чтобы сама собирать дань с других
territories itself because of this Well, let's say  uh
территорий из-за этого было Ну скажем ээ
Khan is an Uzbek, he’s
Хан узбек он
Vovo Just wait, now you’re
вово Вот подожди вот ты сейчас сам вот
writing texts on the go No, that’s what we taught,
ходу тексты пишут Нет это это мы учили
that’s what we studied the history of Russia like, well,
то что мы историю России изучали типа ну
without that first year Look,  who
без этого первый курс Вот смотри кто вас
studied you Well, at the St. Petersburg
изучал Ну в санкт-петербургском
State
государственном
University they can’t study history for each other,
университете там не могут другу историю
they don’t study it Yes, because
изучать не изучают изучаю Да потому что
we have a profile and look, and Uzbek Khan
у нас профильно и смотри и Хан узбек 8
shelled Moscow for 8 years Yes, he
лет обстреливал Москву Да 8 лет
shelled Moscow for 8 years uh He was under siege and
обстреливал Москву э В осаде держал и
then
потом
uh Ivan the Terrible Ivan the Terrible  Yes, and he was
ээ Иван Грозный Иван Грозный Да а он был
also a Tatar, a Tatar, and then the
Ээ тоже татаро татарином это его потом
Orthodox Church named him Ivan
уже православная церковь назвала Иван
so that he was a primate and he was by birth  so uh
чтобы примата и он был по рождению так э
tugay tugay bey tugay bey they called him
тугай тугай бей тугай бей его называли
that's what he was called and in the chronicles there is tugay bey
вот он так и в летописях есть тугай Бей
and then Ivan the Terrible tugay bey Ivan the
а потом Иван Грозный тугай Бей Иван
Terrible So he went to Kazan he went to
Грозный Вот он пошёл на Казань пошёл на
Kazan and captured Kazan That is, it
Казань и захватил Казань То есть это
was a strife between the Tartarian
было между усобица между тартари скими
rulers tugay bey and  Jackie
правителями тугай беем и Джеки
ban look look you can interrupt them
баном смотри смотри можно те перебить
so if Eva Ivan the Terrible is a Tatar  Kazan
так если Ева Иван Грозный татар а Казань
is in Tatarstan, I explain to him to capture
находится в Татарстане ему захватывать
Tatarstan in the same way as for example in
Татарстан объясняю также как например в
Germany some tribes and others fought,
Германии одни племена и другие воевали
look in the Tatars it was all the Great
смотри в татарста это всё была Великая
Ta and in the Great Tartary different
Та да в Великой тартарии разные
princes seemed to fight for who would be the
князья как бы боролись за то кто будет
main prince and in Kazan Kazansky
главным князем и в в Казани Казанский
was juga Bey and  in Moscow there was Grozny, that
был джуга Бей и в Москве был Грозный то
is, Tugai, they were all heirs of
есть тугай они были все наследниками
Mamai, but they were Mamai’s grandchildren, to be sure, even to
мамая вот внуками мамая если точно даже
be Mamai’s grandchildren  and they shared the Mamayian
быть да внуками мамая и делили мамайский
throne because the
престол потому что
Golden Horde
в в Золотой Орде
had a very large economic
был очень большой экономический
potential;
потенциал через золотую арду проходил
the Great Silk Road from China to Europe passed through the Golden Horde.
Великий Шёлковый путь из Китая в Европу
Can I interrupt you? Yes, here you are, as
Можно я тебя перебью Да вот ты вот как
if you had 20% of the Truth.
бы у тебя 20% Правды
20% is 40% meh. Look.  you
20% так это 40% ме Вот смотри ты вот
forgot about how e again Khans bots there
насчёт как е опять забыл Ханы боты там
about how the Golden Horde yes Yes, that
вот насчёт как Золотой Орды да Вот это
was such an Empire, and then he died,
да была такая Империя вот он потом умер
he had three or four there
у него там три или четыре это братья у
their brothers, first of all, they had a relationship with each other and
них во-первых между собой шла и
they had this sweat after this Horde. There they and each
них после этой Орды Там они е друг
other were the only ones who advanced
друга у них единственно там выдвинулся
where. Well, how can you tell, she
куда Ну как ты расскажешь она дотуда
didn’t get there, the sphere of influence didn’t reach, well, wait, how did she
сфера влияния не Доходила ну подожди как
not reach? If you reached Alaska in North
не Доходила Если до Аляски в Северную
America  he himself said that it reached
Америку Ты же сам говорил что Доходила в
North America. It reached so no.
Северную Америку Доходила так нет
I reached you with another question. You
Доходила я тебе другой вопрос ты я тебе
told you about Tartary. And now you’re telling me about
говорил про тартарию А ты мне сейчас про
this, what’s his name, about
это как его
this, how’s his Horde?  so this
про эту как его Орду говоришь так это
is the sweat of the Horde in North America,
есть поте Орды было Северной амери
this is the Golden
это есть Золотая
Horde just in Russia They call it the Golden
Орда просто в России Её называют Золотая
Horde in Europe they called it
Орда в Европе её называли
Tartaria just like look we call
Тартария также как смотри мы называем
Germany Germany the Germans call it
Германию Германия немцы называют её
Deutschland
дойчланд
And this is the same thing here and I
А это одно и тоже так и тут а я её
call it Bavaria Bavaria Yes  also, for
Баварии называю Баварии Да также
example, Mosco was called Tartary. So
например моско называли тартарию Вот и
who is swearing? Wait, show him, show
кто ругается Подожди А ну покажи покажи
him who is swearing, I’ll turn it now, I
его кто ругается я сейчас повор я
’ll ask him, Give it another 5 minutes  Show me I
попрошу его Пусть ещё 5 минут Покажи Я
'll ask him this 5 minutes you give the person
попрошу его это 5 минут даёшь человеку
to speak Well, let's understand yes So
высказаться Ну давай понял да Так вот
by the way, this is how you think
кстати вот как ты считаешь
How many centuries have
Сколько веков существуют
Russians existed Russian or like the Russian state
русские русский или типа государство
Russian I
русский Я
think
думаю лет
200 years So who was there before
200 Так а кто был до
that That's good I want to hear your opinion
этого Вот хорошо Я твоё мнение хочу
Yes I  I think that the Russians
услышать Да я считаю что русских
were invented after Peter first because
придумали после Петра перво потому что
he needed some kind of nationality, I
ему нужно было какую-то национальность
also agree with this, because
воз с этим тоже согласен да потому что
before that there were Merya Meshchera Mordva And
до этого там были меря Мещера Мордва И
so on to Peter  I saw that in
так дальше Петру I он посмотрел что в
Europe everyone would come up with everything there, uh, the
Европе каждый придумают все там ээ были
Bavarians were there, the Saxons came up with the Germans
баварцы там саксон сы придумали немцев
Yes, they were in France There the Burgundians were
Да были во Франции Там бургундцы были
there, they came up with the French, he was
там навар сы придумали французов он
like that And I can’t come up with the
такой А я что не могу придумал
Russians, it’s just that, yes, here we are, I
русских это просто да вот нас чтот это
agree that after Peter
согласен что после Петра
I seemed to unite everyone with similar ones and
I всех как бы на похожих объединили и
that’s it. And with other similar ones they said they were
всё А на других похожих сказали они
Tatars. Well, well, well, I mean. Here I agree with
татары Да ну как ну вот В смысле Тут я с
you, I
тобой
understand. What do you think Peter I
согласен понял А как ты считаешь Пётр I
is  What was his
он Кем был по
nationality, and in general it
национальности а мне вообще
seems to me like Europe? Well, from the West, he’s a German,
кажется Европе Ну оттуда Запада он немец
he’s a
он же
German. Well, yes,
немец А ну да го
and so far, it’s not like he’s definitely not Russian.
и вот пока как бы то не точно не русский
Well, clearly, yes, there
Ну ясно Да так в правительстве России
were never Russians in the Russian government, then there were Germans,
никогда русских не было то были немцы
then this Jew, Lenin, then  this Georgian
потом этот еврей Ленин потом этот грузин
Stalin then the Ukrainian Khrushchev the Ukrainian
Сталин потом украинец Хрущёв украинец
Brezhnev And so on and so this is Andrey
Брежнев И так дальше так вот это Андрей
Tell us that our
Скажи нам что нам этот нашему
long-suffering poor Russian
многострадальному бедному русскому
people need to do
народу делать-то
nothing, we don’t need to do anything anymore
ничего уже не сделать
quickly collapse the Russian
нужно побыстрее развалить Российскую
Federation, that is, look, Peter I took
Федерацию то есть смотри Пётр I взял
everyone into the same, called them Russians, you
всех на одинаковых назвал русскими вам
need to return this process back, that is,
нужно вернуть этот процесс назад то есть
take all the same and divide back the
взять всех одинаковых и разделить назад
Pomors there, the Muscovites of Tver and
поморы там московиты тверцы
these Merya Meshchera And so on That’s all
э эти меря Мещера И так дальше Вот и всё
Oh
А
well, it won’t work, it’ll work Yes  it won’t
ладно так не прокатит прокатит Да не
work Why Because they have already instilled in us everything
прокатит Почему Потому что нам уже всё
that I’ll explain, look with the Spaniards
что объясняю смотри с испанцами
it worked too, it was the Spanish world and that’s it
прокатила тоже было испанский мир и всё
and then what did Cuba do  Argentina Chile
а потом что сделали Куба Аргентина Чили
every other country of the Iro
каждая другая страна иро
until that's when they will fall apart for us all of
пока вот вот когда развалятся у нас всё
this until they fall apart for us all this
это пока не развалятся у нас это всё
too will not collapse so you can't
тоже развала не будет так вы не можете
fall apart even without you can't and
развалиться даже даже без не можете и
fall apart
развалиться
Yes wait for us who to
Да подожди нам на кого
focus on the Spaniards and the Astro
ориентироваться на испанцев тах астро
Hungarian Empire  get your bearings
венгерскую Империю ориентируетесь
Kai avengers
Каю авенгерс
impe history Well, I kind of know too Although in the
импе историю Ну я типа тоже знаю Хотя по
process I don’t know Well, well, here are my words
ходу дела Не знаю Да ну своих слов
Well, I know what the Austro-
вот Ну я знаю что такое Австро
Hungarian Empire is, but no one else
Венгерская империя а больше-то никто не
knows the Ottoman Empire, you can also refer to it
знает Османская империя можете на неё
in the Empire Well, well, well, that
ещё по Империя Ну ну Ну так это ну тоже
was also such an Empire Yes Listen, the question is, what do
была такая Империя Да Слушай а вопрос
you think Russian literature is
как ты считаешь русская литература
Great?
Великая
on the pipe, what
фольга на трубе что это
is it And this is
такое А это
thermal insulation And you see a pipe near the potbelly stove Well,
теплоизоляция А ты у буржуйки трубу
it’s like so that it doesn’t catch fire
видишь Ну это как бы чтоб не загорелось
a little or And this is a
мало или А это
potbelly stove this is a potbelly stove yes A  show me I've
буржуйка это буржуйка да А покажи Я
never seen a potbelly stove
никогда не видел буржуйку
here, you see this here, Putin gave us the Internet,
у нас видишь это у нас Путин интернет
but I didn't supply the gas,
дал а газ не провёл
I'm at
я те сейчас у
Nasri's now. I told you that
Насри Я же тебе говорил да что интернет
we have the Internet, here I showed you. Here I'll
есть у нас вот показывал У нас вот
show you now. And this is where you
сейчас покажу тебе А это где ты
are in general, I  I told you I
находишься вообще я же тебе сказал я в
’m in the tundra And I’m like, you’re at
тундре нахожусь А внем ну типа ты на
work on a shift somewhere Yes, you see, no, you’re
работе на вахте где-то Да види нет
stuck, you’re stuck,
нерета позвони
you see, no, Yes, I
при сам застрял видишь жито нет Да
see, Everything now Putin
вижу Всё теперь Путин интернет
has taken away the Internet Salam aleikum  Alek
забрал Салам алейкум алеку
Well done in the tundra with a potbelly stove
Молодец в тундре с буржуйкой
A tin like pska comment subscribe to th
А жесть лайк пска комент подпишись на й
Telegram right now axis VN and popk
Telegram прямо зараз ось ВН а попк
tse more and more respectfully YouTube taking us
це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня нас
through skargor to the new ban and even more
через скарг ор в ньй бан и дуже багато
videos I don’t show people sometimes I don’t show
вдео не показую людям вчасно не показуе
information about streams For Tom  In addition,
информация про стрими Тому для того щоб
we need to write an operational link in Mali
ми Мали оперативный звязок пишиться
directly at the same time  there in telegra okm
прямо зараз а пок там в телегра окм
video sche tezh va and korisna information and
видео ще теж ва и корисна информация и
we will call you trima postiyny
мы пон з вами трима постийний
operational link
оперативный звязок
nezalezhno in that chi show you about it
незалежно в того чи покаже вам про це
YouTube Glory to Ukraine
YouTube Слава Украине
pipis Y
пидпись Y